<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-transitional.dtd">
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
	xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
	xmlns:skos="http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/core#"
	xmlns:time="https://www.w3.org/TR/owl-time/"
	xmlns:ies="http://ies.data.gov.uk/ies4#"
	>
<head>
<meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html; charset=UTF-8" />
<link type="text/css" href="../master.css" rel="stylesheet"/>
<title>Roles</title>
<link rel="schema.DC" href="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"/>
<meta name="DC.source" content="The Elephant and the Fly"/>
<meta name="DC.identifier" content="Example ..."/>
</head>
<body>

<h1>Roles</h1>

<p class="note">
The HTML <em>articles</em> on this page are of type ies:State. Claims are facts about entities expressed in the present tense. Facts expressed in an article are assumed to be consistent. Facts across different articles are only assumed to be consistent if the states associated with each article are consistent. Here, that means the articles describe states at "about the same time".
</p>

<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book1.xhtml#3">Tacitus, Annals 1.3</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:1.3">
		<blockquote>
		And yet Augustus had appointed Germanicus, Drusus's offspring, to the command of eight legions on the Rhine,<span class="ellipsis"> ...</span>
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Germanicus</span> is in command of <span class="unit">eight legions</span> in <span class="place">Germany</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book1.xhtml#7">Tacitus, Annals 1.7</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:1.7">
		<blockquote>
		Sextus Pompeius and Sextus Apuleius, the consuls, were the first to swear allegiance to Tiberius Caesar, and in their presence the oath was taken by Seius Strabo and Caius Turranius, respectively the commander of the praetorian cohorts and the superintendent of the corn supplies.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Seius Strabo</span> is in command of the <span class="unit">Praetorian Guard</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Caius Turranius</span> is <span class="role">superintendent of the corn supplies</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book1.xhtml#24">Tacitus, Annals 1.24</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:1.24">
		<blockquote>
		With them too was the commander of the praetorians, Aelius Sejanus, who had been associated with his own father, Strabo, had great influence with Tiberius, and was to advise and direct the young prince, and to hold out punishment or reward to the soldiers.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Aelius Sejanus</span> is in command of the <span class="unit">Praetorian Guard</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book1.xhtml#31">Tacitus, Annals 1.31</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:1.31">
		<blockquote>
		There were two armies on the bank of the Rhine; that named the upper army had Caius Silius for general; the lower was under the charge of Aulus Caecina. The supreme direction rested with Germanicus, then busily employed in conducting the assessment of Gaul.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Caius Silius</span> is in command of the <span class="unit">upper army</span>, stationed in <span class="place">Germany</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Aulus Caecina</span> is in command of the <span class="unit">lower army</span>, stationed in <span class="place">Germany</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Germanicus</span> is superior to <span class="person">Caius Silius</span> and <span class="person">Aulus Caecina</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:1.31">	
		<blockquote>
		The troops under the control of Silius, with minds yet in suspense, watched the issue of mutiny elsewhere; but the soldiers of the lower army fell into a frenzy, which had its beginning in the men of the twenty first and fifth legions, and into which the first and twentieth were also drawn. For they were all quartered in the same summer-camp, in the territory of the Ubii, enjoying ease or having only light duties.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					The <span class="unit">twenty-first legion</span> is part of the <span class="unit">lower army</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					The <span class="unit">fifth legion</span> is part of the <span class="unit">lower army</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					The <span class="unit">first legion</span> is part of the <span class="unit">lower army</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					The <span class="unit">twentieth legion</span> is part of the <span class="unit">lower army</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>

<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book1.xhtml#37">Tacitus, Annals 1.37</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:1.37">
		<blockquote>
		Germanicus went to the Upper Army, and the second, thirteenth, and sixteenth legions, without any delay, accepted from him the oath of allegiance. The fourteenth hesitated a little, but their money and the discharge were offered even without their demanding it.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					The <span class="unit">second legion</span> is part of the <span class="unit">upper army</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					The <span class="unit">thirteenth legion</span> is part of the <span class="unit">upper army</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					The <span class="unit">sixteenth legion</span> is part of the <span class="unit">upper army</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					The <span class="unit">fourteenth legion</span> is part of the <span class="unit">upper army</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>

<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book1.xhtml#16">Tacitus, Annals 1.16</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:1.16">
		<blockquote>
		This was the state of affairs at Rome when a mutiny broke out in the legions of Pannonia, <span class="ellipsis"> ... </span> In the summer camp three legions were quartered, under the command of Junius Blaesus, <span class="ellipsis"> ... </span>
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Junius Blaesus</span> is in command of <span class="unit">three legions</span> in <span class="place">Pannonia</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book1.xhtml#23">Tacitus, Annals 1.23</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:1.23">
		<blockquote>
		Two legions, the eighth and the fifteenth, were actually drawing swords against each other, the former demanding the death of a centurion, whom they nicknamed Sirpicus, while the men of the fifteenth defended him, but the soldiers of the ninth interposed their entreaties, and when these were disregarded, their menaces.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					The <span class="unit">eighth legion</span> is stationed in <span class="place">Pannonia</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					The <span class="unit">fifteenth legion</span> is stationed in <span class="place">Pannonia</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					The <span class="unit">ninth legion</span> is stationed in <span class="place">Pannonia</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book1.xhtml#44">Tacitus, Annals 1.44</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:1.44">
		<blockquote>
		Away they hurried hither and thither, altered men, and dragged the chief mutineers in chains to Caius Caetronius, commander of the first legion, who tried and punished them one by one in the following fashion.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Caius Caetronius</span> is in commmand of the <span class="unit">first legion</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book2.xhtml#2">Tacitus, Annals 2.2</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:2.2">
		<blockquote>
		After the death of Phraates and the succeeding kings in the bloodshed of civil wars, there came to Rome envoys from the chief men of Parthia, in quest of Vonones, his eldest son. Caesar thought this a great honour to himself, and loaded Vonones with wealth. The barbarians, too, welcomed him with rejoicing, as is usual with new rulers.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person" content="Phraates IV">Phraates</span> is <span class="role">king of Parthia</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person" content="Vonones I">Vonones</span> is the son of <span class="person" content="Phraates IV">Phraates</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person" content="Vonones I">Vonones</span> succeeds <span class="person" content="Phraates IV">Phraates</span> as <span class="role">king of Parthia</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="rewrite">"Phraates" refers to <span class="name">Phraates IV</span>.</p>
			<p class="rewrite">"Vonones" refers to <span class="name">Vonones I</span>.</p>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book2.xhtml#3">Tacitus, Annals 2.3</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:2.3">
		<blockquote>
		Accordingly they summoned Artabanus, an Arsacid by blood, who had grown to manhood among the Dahae, and who, though routed in the first encounter, rallied his forces and possessed himself of the kingdom. The conquered Vonones found a refuge in Armenia, then a free country, and exposed to the power of Parthia and Rome, without being trusted by either,<span class="ellipsis"> ...</span>
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person" content="Artabanus II">Artabanus</span> succeeds <span class="person" content="Vonones I">Vonones</span> as <span class="role">king of Parthia</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person" content="Vonones I">Vonones</span> seeks refuge in <span class="place">Armenia</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="rewrite">"Vonones" refers to <span class="name">Vonones I</span>.</p>
			<p class="rewrite">"Artabanus" refers to <span class="name">Artabanus II</span>.</p>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="note">Some time earlier ...</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:2.3">
		<blockquote>
		<span class="ellipsis"> ...</span>, without being trusted by either, in consequence of the crime of Antonius, who, under the guise of friendship, had inveigled Artavasdes, king of the Armenians, then loaded him with chains, and finally murdered him. His son, Artaxias, our bitter foe because of his father's memory, found defence for himself and his kingdom in the might of the Arsacids. When he was slain by the treachery of kinsmen, Caesar gave Tigranes to the Armenians, and he was put in possession of the kingdom under the escort of Tiberius Nero. But neither Tigranes nor his children reigned long, though, in foreign fashion, they were united in marriage and in royal power.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person" content="Artavasdes II">Artavasdes</span> is <span class="role">king of Armenia</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person" content="Vonones I">Artaxias</span> is the son of <span class="person" content="Phraates IV">Artavasdes</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person" content="Artaxias II">Artaxias</span> succeeds <span class="person" content="Artavasdes II">Artavasdes</span> as <span class="role">king of Armenia</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person" content="Tigranes III">Tigranes</span> succeeds <span class="person" content="Artaxias II">Artaxias</span> as <span class="role">king of Armenia</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
			<p>
				<span class="rewrite">"Artavasdes" refers to <span class="name">Artavasdes II</span></span>;
				<span class="rewrite">"Artaxias" refers to <span class="name">Artaxias II</span></span>;
				<span class="rewrite">"Tigranes" refers to <span class="name">Tigranes III</span></span>.
			</p>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book2.xhtml#4">Tacitus, Annals 2.4</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:2.4">
		<blockquote>
		Next, at the bidding of Augustus, Artavasdes was set on the throne, nor was he deposed without disaster to ourselves. Caius Caesar was then appointed to restore order in Armenia. He put over the Armenians Ariobarzanes, a Mede by birth, whom they willingly accepted, because of his singularly handsome person and noble spirit. On the death of Ariobarzanes through a fatal accident, they would not endure his son. Having tried the government of a woman named Erato and having soon afterwards driven her from them, bewildered and disorganised, rather indeed without a ruler than enjoying freedom, they received for their king the fugitive Vonones.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ol>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person" content="Ariobarzanes II of Atropatene">Ariobarzanes</span> becomes <span class="role">king of Armenia</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					The <span class="person">son of Ariobarzanes</span> becomes <span class="role">king of Armenia</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Erato</span> becomes <span class="role">queen of Armenia</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person" content="Vonones I">Vonones</span> becomes <span class="role">king of Armenia</span>.
				</li>
			</ol>
			<p>
				<span class="rewrite">"Ariobarzanes" refers to <span class="name">Ariobarzanes II of Atropatene</span>.</span>
				<span class="rewrite">"Vonones" refers to <span class="name">Vonones I</span>.</span>
			</p>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book2.xhtml#42">Tacitus, Annals 2.42</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:2.42">
		<blockquote>
		King Archelaus had been in possession of Cappadocia for fifty years,<span class="ellipsis"> ...</span>
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Archelaus</span> is <span class="role">king of Cappadocia</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:2.42">
		<blockquote>
		During the same time, on the deaths of Antiochus and Philopator, kings respectively of the Commageni and Cilicians, these nations became excited, a majority desiring the Roman rule, some, that of their kings.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person" content="Antiochus III">Antiochus</span> is <span class="role">king of Commagene</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person" content="Philopator II">Philopator</span> is <span class="role">king of Cilicia</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book2.xhtml#56">Tacitus, Annals 2.56</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:2.42">
		<blockquote>
		It had at this time no king, Vonones having been expelled, but the nation's likings inclined towards Zeno, son of Polemon, king of Pontus, who from his earliest infancy had imitated Armenian manners and customs, loving the chase, the banquet, and all the popular pastimes of barbarians, and who had thus bound to himself chiefs and people alike. Germanicus accordingly, in the city of Artaxata, with the approval of the nobility, in the presence of a vast multitude, placed the royal diadem on his head. All paid him homage and saluted him as King Artaxias, which name they gave him from the city.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person" content="Vonones I">Vonones</span> is no longer <span class="role">king of Armenia</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person" content="Polemon I of Pontus">Polemon</span> is <span class="role">king of Pontus</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person" content="Artaxias III">Zeno</span> is the son of <span class="role" content="Polemon I of Pontus">Polemon</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person" content="Artaxias III">Artaxias</span> is <span class="role">king of Armenia</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
			<p>
				<span class="rewrite">"Vonones" refer to <span class="name">Vonones I</span></span>.
				<span class="rewrite">"Zeno" and "Artaxias" refer to <span class="name">Artaxias III</span></span>;
				<span class="rewrite">"Polemon" refers to <span class="name">Polemon I of Pontus</span></span>.
			</p>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book2.xhtml#79">Tacitus, Annals 2.79</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:2.79">
		<blockquote>
		Meanwhile Domitius having landed at Laodicea, a city of Syria, as he was on his way to the winter-quarters of the sixth legion, which was, he believed, particularly open to revolutionary schemes, was anticipated by its commander Pacuvius.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="nlp">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="place">Laodicea</span> is a city in <span class="place">Syria</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Pacuvius</span> is in commmand of the <span class="unit">sixth legion</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book4.xhtml#1">Tacitus, Annals 4.1</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:4.1">
		<blockquote>
		Of this the cause and origin was Aelius Sejanus, commander of the praetorian cohorts, of whose influence I have already spoken.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Aelius Sejanus</span> is in commmand of the <span class="unit">Praetorian Guard</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book4.xhtml#73">Tacitus, Annals 4.73</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:4.73">
		<blockquote>
		As soon as this was known to Lucius Apronius, pro-praetor of Lower Germany, he summoned from the Upper province the legionary veterans, as well as some picked auxiliary infantry and cavalry.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Lucius Apronius</span> is in commmand of the <span class="unit">lower army</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:4.73">
		<blockquote>
		Apronius entrusted the rest of the auxiliaries to Cethegus Labeo, the commander of the fifth legion,<span class="ellipsis"> ...</span>
	</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Cethegus Labeo</span> is in commmand of the <span class="unit">fifth legion</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book6.xhtml#15">Tacitus, Annals 6.15</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:6.15">
		<blockquote>
		He next assigned some very vague reasons for his absence, then passed to more important matters, the ill-will against him originating in his state policy, and requested that Macro, who commanded the praetorians, with a few tribunes and centurions, might accompany him whenever he entered the Senate-house.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Macro</span> is in commmand of the <span class="unit">Praetorian Guard</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book11.xhtml#1">Tacitus, Annals 11.1</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:11.1">
		<blockquote>
		Claudius made no further inquiry, but sent Crispinus, commander of the Praetorians, with troops in hot haste, as though to put down a revolt. Crispinus found him at Baiae, loaded him with chains, and hurried him to Rome.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Rufius Crispinus</span> is in commmand of the <span class="unit">Praetorian Guard</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book11.xhtml#31">Tacitus, Annals 11.31</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:11.31">
		<blockquote>
		First he questioned Turranius, superintendent of the corn market; next, Lusius Geta, who commanded the praetorians.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Caius Turranius</span> is <span class="role">superintendent of the corn supplies</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Lusius Geta</span> is in commmand of the <span class="unit">Praetorian Guard</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book12.xhtml#40">Tacitus, Annals 12.40</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:12.40">
		<blockquote>
		The emperor on hearing of the death of his representative appointed Aulus Didius in his place, that the province might not be left without a governor. Didius, though he quickly arrived, found matters far from prosperous, for the legion under the command of Manlius Valens had meanwhile been defeated, <span class="ellipsis">...</span>
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Manlius Valens</span> is in commmand of <span class="unit" content="an unknown legion">an unknown legion in <span class="place">Britain</span></span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:12.40">
		<blockquote>
		The legion under the command of Caesius Nasica fought with a similar result.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Caesius Nasica</span> is in commmand of <span class="unit" content="an unknown legion">an unknown legion in <span class="place">Britain</span></span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book12.xhtml#42">Tacitus, Annals 12.42</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:12.42">
		<blockquote>
		till Agrippina did not yet dare to attempt her greatest scheme, unless Lusius Geta and Rufius Crispinus were removed from the command of the praetorian cohorts; for she thought that they cherished Messalina's memory and were devoted to her children.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Lusius Geta</span> is in commmand of the <span class="unit">Praetorian Guard</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Rufius Crispinus</span> is in commmand of the <span class="unit">Praetorian Guard</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book12.xhtml#44">Tacitus, Annals 12.44</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:12.44">
		<blockquote>
		Vologeses was king of the Parthians; on the mother's side, he was the offspring of a Greek concubine, and he obtained the throne by the retirement of his brothers. Pharasmanes had been long in possession of Iberia, and his brother, Mithridates, ruled Armenia with our powerful support.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person" content="Vologeses I">Vologeses</span> is <span class="role">king of Parthia</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person" content="Pharasmanes I">Pharasmanes</span> is <span class="role">king of Iberia</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person" content="Mithridates of Armenia">Mithridates</span> is <span class="role">king of Armenia</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person" content="Mithridates of Armenia">Mithridates</span> is the brother of <span class="person" content="Pharasmanes I">Pharasmanes</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
			<p>
				<span class="rewrite">"Vologeses" refers to <span class="name">Vologeses I</span></span>.
				<span class="rewrite">"Pharasmanes" refers to <span class="name">Pharasmanes I</span></span>.
				<span class="rewrite">"Mithridates" refers to <span class="name">Mithridates of Armenia</span></span>.
			</p>
		</div>
	</div>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:12.44">
		<blockquote>
		There was a son of Pharasmanes named Rhadamistus,<span class="ellipsis"> ...</span>
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Rhadamistus</span> is the son of <span class="person" content="Pharasmanes I">Pharasmanes</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book12.xhtml#48">Tacitus, Annals 12.48</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:12.48">
		<blockquote>
		Quadratus, learning that Mithridates had been betrayed and that his kingdom was in the hands of his murderers, summoned a council, and, having informed them of what had occurred, consulted them whether he should take vengeance.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					The death of <span class="person" content="Mithridates of Armenia">Mithridates</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Rhadamistus</span> is <span class="role">king of Armenia</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
			<p>
				<span class="rewrite">"Mithridates" refers to <span class="name">Mithridates of Armenia</span></span>.
			</p>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:Event">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book13.xhtml#6">Tacitus, Annals 13.6</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:13.6">
		<blockquote>
		With the close of the year came disquieting rumours that the Parthians had again broken their bounds and were ravaging Armenia, from which they had driven Rhadamistus, who, having often possessed himself of the kingdom and as often been thrust out of it, had now relinquished hostilities.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="unit">Parthian troops</span> invade <span class="place">Armenia</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Rhadamistus</span> is no longer <span class="role">king of Armenia</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book13.xhtml#7">Tacitus, Annals 13.7</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:13.7">
		<blockquote>
		Lesser Armenia was intrusted to Aristobulus, Sophene to Sohaemus, each with the ensigns of royalty.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Aristobulus</span> is <span class="role">king of Lesser Armenia</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Sohaemus</span> is <span class="role">king of Sophene</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>
<article typeof="ies:Event">
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:13.7">
		<blockquote>
		There rose up at this crisis a rival to Vologeses in his son Vardanes, and the Parthians quitted Armenia, apparently intending to defer hostilities.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Vardanes</span> is the son of <span class="person">Vologeses</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="unit">Parthian troops</span> withdraw from <span class="place">Armenia</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
			<p>
				<span class="rewrite">"Vardanes" refers to <span class="name">Vardanes II</span></span>;
				<span class="rewrite">"Vologeses" refers to <span class="name">Vologeses I</span></span>.
			</p>

		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book13.xhtml#8">Tacitus, Annals 13.8</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:13.8">
		<blockquote>
		To their habitual flattery was added a real joy at his having appointed Domitius Corbulo to secure Armenia, thus opening, as it seemed, a field to merit. The armies of the East were so divided that half the auxiliaries and two legions were to remain in the province of Syria under its governor, Quadratus Ummidius; while Corbulo was to have an equal number of citizen and allied troops, together with the auxiliary infantry and cavalry which were in winter quarters in Cappadocia.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Domitius Corbulo</span> is appointed to restore order in <span class="place">Armenia</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Quadratus Ummidius</span> is <span class="role">governor of Syria</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book13.xhtml#15">Tacitus, Annals 13.15</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:13.15">
		<blockquote>
		Pressed by Agrippina's menaces, having no charge against his brother and not daring openly to order his murder, he meditated a secret device and directed poison to be prepared through the agency of Julius Pollio, tribune of one of the praetorian cohorts, who had in his custody a woman under sentence for poisoning, Locusta by name, with a vast reputation for crime.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Julius Pollio</span> is a <span class="role">tribune of a praetorian cohort</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book13.xhtml#28">Tacitus, Annals 13.28</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:13.28">
		<blockquote>
		A contest arose between Vibullius, the praetor, and Antistius, a tribune of the people; <span class="ellipsis"> ... </span>It was further proposed by Lucius Piso, consul-elect, that tribunes were not to try any case in their own houses,<span class="ellipsis"> ... </span>
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Vibullius</span> is <span class="role">praetor</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Antistius</span> is a <span class="role">tribune of the people</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Lucius Piso</span> is <span class="role">consul-elect</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:13.28">
		<blockquote>
		On this, Helvidius Priscus, a tribune of the people, followed up a personal quarrel he had with Obultronius Sabinus, one of the officials of the exchequer,<span class="ellipsis"> ...</span>
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Helvidius Priscus</span> is a <span class="role">tribune of the people</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Obultronius Sabinus</span> is an <span class="role">official of the exchequer</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book13.xhtml#56">Tacitus, Annals 13.56</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:13.56">
		<blockquote>
		Avitus, having written to Curtilius Mancia, commander of the Upper army, asking him to cross the Rhine and display his troops in the enemy's rear, himself led his legions into the territory of the Tencteri, and threatened them with extermination unless they dissociated themselves from the cause.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Curtilius Mancia</span> is in commmand of the <span class="unit">upper army</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book14.xhtml#32">Tacitus, Annals 14.32</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:14.32">
		<blockquote>
		The victorious enemy met Petilius Cerialis, commander of the ninth legion, as he was coming to the rescue, routed his troops, and destroyed all his infantry.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Petilius Cerialis</span> is in commmand of the <span class="unit">ninth legion</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book14.xhtml#34">Tacitus, Annals 14.34</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:14.34">
		<blockquote>
		Suetonius had the fourteenth legion with the veterans of the twentieth, and auxiliaries from the neighbourhood, to the number of about ten thousand armed men, when he prepared to break off delay and fight a battle.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Suetonius Paulinus</span> is in commmand of the <span class="unit">fourteenth legion</span> and parts of the <span class="unit">twentieth legion</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book14.xhtml#51">Tacitus, Annals 14.51</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:14.51">
		<blockquote>
		For the emperor had appointed two men to the command of the praetorian cohorts, Faenius Rufus, for a vulgar popularity, which he owed to his administration of the corn-supplies without profit to himself; and Sofonius Tigellinus, whose inveterate shamelessness and infamy were an attraction to him. As might have been expected from their known characters, Tigellinus had the greater influence with the prince, and was the associate of his most secret profligacy, while Rufus enjoyed the favour of the people and of the soldiers, and this, he found, prejudiced him with Nero.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Faenius Rufus</span> is a former <span class="unit">superintendent of the corn supplies</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Faenius Rufus</span> is in commmand of the <span class="unit">Praetorian Guard</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Sofonius Tigellinus</span> is in commmand of the <span class="unit">Praetorian Guard</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book15.xhtml#1">Tacitus, Annals 15.1</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:15.1">
		<blockquote>
		Meanwhile, the Parthian king, Vologeses, when he heard of Corbulo's achievements and of a foreign prince, Tigranes, having been set over Armenia, <span class="ellipsis"> ... </span> Their anger was inflamed by Monobazus, who ruled the Adiabeni,<span class="ellipsis"> ... </span>
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Vologeses</span> is <span class="role">king of Parthia</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Tigranes</span> is <span class="role">king of Armenia</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Monobazus</span> is <span class="role">king of Adiabene</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book15.xhtml#2">Tacitus, Annals 15.2</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:15.2">
		<blockquote>
		As for Media, Pacorus was already in possession of it. 
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Pacorus</span> is <span class="role">king of Media</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book15.xhtml#3">Tacitus, Annals 15.3</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:15.3">
		<blockquote>
		When Corbulo had heard all this from messengers he could trust, he sent two legions under Verulanus Severus and Vettius Bolanus to the support of Tigranes,<span class="ellipsis"> ... </span>
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Verulanus Severus</span> is in command of <span class="unit" >a legion</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Vettius Bolanus</span> is in command of <span class="unit" >a legion</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book15.xhtml#6">Tacitus, Annals 15.6</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:15.6">
		<blockquote>
		<span class="ellipsis">... </span>and it was heard that Caesennius Paetus was on his way. And indeed he had now arrived, and the army was thus divided; the fourth and twelfth legions, with the fifth which had lately been raised in Moesia and the auxiliaries from Pontus, Galatia and Cappadocia, were under the command of Paetus, while the third, sixth, and tenth legions and the old soldiery of Syria remained with Corbulo.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Caesennius Paetus</span> is in command of the <span class="unit" content="fourth legion">fourth</span>, <span class="unit" content="twelfth legion">twelfth</span> and <span class="unit" content="fifth legion">fifth</span> legions in <span class="place">Syria</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Corbulo</span> is in command of the <span class="unit" content="third legion">third</span>, <span class="unit" content="sixth legion">sixth</span> and <span class="unit" content="tenth legion">tenth</span> legions in <span class="place">Syria</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book15.xhtml#7">Tacitus, Annals 15.7</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:15.7">
		<blockquote>
		Nor did Paetus decline the challenge, but with two legions, the 4th and 12th, the first of which was then commanded by Funisulanus Vettonianus and the second by Calavius Sabinus, entered Armenia, with unlucky omen.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Funisulanus Vettonianus</span> is in command of the <span class="unit">fourth legion</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Calavius Sabinus</span> is in command of the <span class="unit">twelfth legion</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book15.xhtml#28">Tacitus, Annals 15.28</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:15.28">
		<blockquote>
		On the day appointed, Tiberius Alexander, a distinguished Roman knight, sent to assist in the campaign, and Vinianus Annius, Corbulo's son-in-law, who, though not yet of a senator's age, had the command of the fifth legion as "legatus," entered the camp of Tiridates, by way of compliment to him, and to reassure him against treachery by so valuable a pledge.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Vinianus Annius</span> is in command of the <span class="unit">fifth legion</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book15.xhtml#49">Tacitus, Annals 15.49</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:15.49">
		<blockquote>
		That the leading spirits were Subrius Flavus, tribune of a praetorian cohort, and Sulpicius Asper, a centurion, was proved by the fearlessness of their death.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Subrius Flavus</span> is <span class="role">tribune of a praetorian cohort</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Sulpicius Asper</span> is a <span class="role">centurion</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book15.xhtml#50">Tacitus, Annals 15.50</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:15.50">
		<blockquote>
		Besides Subrius and Sulpicius, whom I have already mentioned, they invited the aid of military strength, of Gavius Silvanus and Statius Proximus, tribunes of praetorian cohorts, and of two centurions, Maximus Scaurus and Venetus Paulus.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Gavius Silvanus</span> is <span class="role">tribune of a praetorian cohort</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Statius Proximus</span> is <span class="role">tribune of a praetorian cohort</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Maximus Scaurus</span> is a <span class="role">centurion</span>.
				</li>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Venetus Paulus</span> is a <span class="role">centurion</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book15.xhtml#72">Tacitus, Annals 15.72</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:15.72">
		<blockquote>
		Then, as if he was going to describe successes in war, he summoned the Senate, and awarded triumphal honours to Petronius Turpilianus, an ex-consul, to Cocceius Nerva, praetor-elect, and to Tigellinus, commander of the praetorians.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Sofonius Tigellinus</span> is in commmand of the <span class="unit">Praetorian Guard</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

<hr/>
<article typeof="ies:State">
	<p class="ref"><a href="https://knoxa.github.io/text/tacitus/annals/book15.xhtml#74">Tacitus, Annals 15.74</a>:</p>
	<div about="urn:cts:latinLit:phi1351.phi005.perseus-eng1:15.74">
		<blockquote>
		I find in the registers of the Senate that Cerialis Anicius, consul-elect, proposed a motion that a temple should as soon as possible be built at the public expense to the Divine Nero.
		</blockquote>
		<div class="analysis">
			<ul>
				<li class="claim">
					<span class="person">Cerialis Anicius</span> is <span class="role">consul-elect</span>.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</div>
	</div>
</article>

</body>
</html>